Guide to the Leonor Villegas de Magnón Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Photographs
  - Identified Photographs (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Photo of store. Back of the picture: Note the improvement in our shop. X is the Studio and Mr. Conn, the professor. Mr. Vidaurri is standing at the Supreme (Itain) Remedy Dept. Mrs. L. I. Blake at the house hold and interior Decorating Dept. Mrs. De la Garza is visiting us (at the phone) and tours trulyCapt. Of the ship. XXX is xxx soliciting. (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 13)
    - Group photo. Back of the picture: Dr. Cook’s brother (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 14)
    - Ruiz Cortines. Political campaign. Postcard (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 15)
    - Portrait of a general. Back of the picture: Gral. Elizondo who gave Rebel cars to move her 60 wounded soldiers to Mex City. (Provided automobiles). (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 16)
    - Portrait of three men. Caption: Esquero, Feliberto Villarreal, Perrusqui. Back of picture: Feliclós Villarreal. Perrusquia (left). Lic Esquierro (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 17)
    - Portrait. Signed: Espinosa. Back of the picture: Para la muy estimable señora (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 18)
    - Postcard. Portrait of Ramón Franco. Caption: A Leonor Villegas de Magnón. Blanca mano, dulce mano piadosa, alma buena, bajo su misericordia pongo mi espíritu. Ramón Franco. Torreón VI-2-914 (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 19)
    - Family Photo. Caption: Gral. Pablo de la Garza and family (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 20)
    - Portrait Benjamín Garza. Caption: Benjamín Garza. Para la Sra. Leonor Villegas de Magnón. Laredo, Tamps. 15 1915 (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 21)
    - Dog Photo. Perro artillero “El Marqués” Foto A. S. Back of the picture: El marqués, perro que en los combates de Monclova Candela y Hermanas ha servido para transmitir órdenes llevándolas por las calles todavía en poder del enemigo (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 22)
    - Signed portrait of General Murrieta. Back of the picture: Marcilino Murrieta (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 23)
    - Postcard. F. R. Musquiz in a horse. Caption: Capt. 1o F. R. Musquiz. Constitucionalista (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 24)
    - Signed portrait of Felix F. Palavicini. Caption: Mexico IV. (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 25)
    - Group photo. Back of the picture: Andrés Patiño Felipe Zepeda. (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 26)
    - Postcard. Portrait of General de Brigada Ignacio L. Pesqueira (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 27)
    - Portrait. Postcard Caption: 1913. General de Brigada Ignacio L. Pesqueira. (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 28)
    - Portrait. Caption: Para mi estimada amiga y correligionaria Sra. Leonor Villegas de Magnón. 11-1-917. Back of the postcard: Postmaster General during Pres. V. Carranza administration (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 29)
    - Portrait of a man sitting. Back of the picture: Dr. José María Rodríguez (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 30)
    - Group photo. Back of the picture: Pastor Rouiax, Ministro de Fomento – Saltillo. Peter Floyed, Ernestina Flores, Srita. Carranza. X not identified. (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 31)
    - Portrait of Aquiles Serdán. Caption: Aquiles Serdán. Puebla Nov 18 de 1910. Postcard (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 32)
    - Portrait of Francesco Tamagno. Caption: Comm. Francesco Tamagno. Postcard (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 33)
    - Portrait of Samuel G. Vazquez. Caption: Ejército Constitucionalista. Mayor (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 34)
    - Portrait Antonio I. Villarreal. Caption: Antonio I. Villarreal candidato a senador. Back of the campaign picture: Datos Biográficos de Antonio I. Villarreal. Candidato a senador por el estado de Nuevo León. (Box 7, Folder 6, Item 35)
  - Unidentified Photographs (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Four gentlemen after lunch (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 1)
    - Portrait Coronel XXX. Caption: Recuerdo Coronel (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 2)
    - Family photo beside a train (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 3)
    - Group Photo. Postcard. (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 4)
    - Group Photo. Unknown. Postcard (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 5)
    - Group Photo of unknown men. Back of the postcard: F. (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 6)
    - Unknown portrait (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 7)
    - Group photo. Caption: Foto A. S. Otro número de la fiesta en San Antonio antisipando (sic) festejo de Candela. (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 8)
    - Portrait of unknown man. Back of the postcard: A la ilustrada y virtuosa Señora Leonor Villegas de Magnón, con mi afecto más respetuoso y mi admiración más sincera por su “obra pía” – importantísima como incansable Presidenta de la Cruz Roja Nacional. Su axxxx amigo. C. Ignacio Magalmi (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 9)
    - Photo of a group of people, mainly men (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 10)
    - Picture of a uniformed man and two women. Left: (García?) Castro (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 11)
    - Postcard. Portrait of a Group of military men. Back of the picture: Estado Mayor del General Manzo (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 12)
    - Color portrait of military man. Back of picture: Carlos Fierros. Property of Mrs. Gordiabo Vela (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 13)
    - Unknown portrait (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 14)
    - Group Photo of military men. Caption: xxxxxxx Coahuila (Box 7, Folder 7, Item 15)
  - Still Life, Landscapes, Other (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Postcard. Photo of ship. Caption: Hadsell. Cruz 3 (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 1)
    - Kennedy home. Caption Kennedy Home Matamoros and Davis (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 2)
    - Photo of a church. Caption: San Agustín (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 3)
    - Image of the Virgin of Guadalupe (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 4)
    - Image of Jesus Christ (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 5)
    - International bridge over the Rio Bravo/Grande (Laredo to Nuevo Laredo), 1912 (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 6)
    - Placa conmemorativa. Caption: Conmemorativa en la estatua de Juárez en Colima por la revolución (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 7)
    - Postcard. Coche de Juárez. Carroza Maximiliano. Caption: Enero 1904. Ignacio M. Luchichí. Soledad Juárez de Luchichí. Back: Mr. and Mrs. Magnón y fam. Ciudad. 1ª Pane no. 1642 (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 8)
    - Trench (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 9)
    - Caption: Monumento a Juárez erigido en Colima por el gobierno revolucionario (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 10)
    - Landscape. Destroyed house (Box 7, Folder 8, Item 11)
  - Photocopies of Photographs in Collection (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Oversize Photographs (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Celebration with the General Muzquiz Chavez Band July 17, 1914 (Leonor seated at left side of boxcar door) (Box 7, Folder 10, Item 1)
    - Group Photo. From left to right: Lily Long, Dr. Rodríguez, Leonor Villegas de Magnón, Venustiano Carranza, General Gregorio Osuna. Durango 1913 (Box 7, Folder 10, Item 2)
    - Signed portrait of Manuel Chao. Caption: Como una demostración de alta simpatÍa dedico este recuerdo a la Sra. Leonor Villegas de Magnón. Torreón Coah. Mayo 8, 1914. Manuel Chao. (Box 7, Folder 10, Item 3)
    - Venustiano Carranza's signed portrait. Caption: A mi estimade amiga Sra. Leonor Villegas de Magnón. V. Carranza. México Fbre 11 de 1914 (Box 7, Folder 10, Item 4)